## DAVID L WARNER

Interaction Designer and Front-End Developer

362 Missouri Street
San Francisco, cA 94107
(415) 609-7490
david@davidlwarner.com
http://davidlwarner.com

## **PROFILE**

I'm an interaction designer and front-end engineer with a decade of experience managing teams and projects. I focus on the intersection of clean design and clean code. I'm happiest when I'm creating consumer web applications and collaborating with a strong team to simplify the complex and to make people's lives better. I've worked with Adaptive Path, Allstate, Crowdcast, the Metropolitan Opera, Ning, and RealNetworks. In my spare time, I geek out on music. See my work at http://davidlwarner.com.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Freelance Interaction Designer & Front-End Developer — 2010–2011

Interaction design and front-end development focused on early-stage start-ups building their initial products.

- Collaborated with clients and Rails developers to rapidly develop minimum viable products
- Recently launched LoudSauce, which enables crowd-funded advertising on TV, billboards and print media for non-profits and social good

Interaction Designer at Crowdcast — 2010

I was the interaction and graphic designer for Crowdcast, a small startup that helps F500 companies like Electronic Arts, Hallmark, GM, and Oracle determine more accurate forecasts by aggregating employee knowledge through prediction markets.

- Redesigned the product to greatly improve usability, which led to much higher usage
- Ran usability studies and product experiments to find product-market fit

Lead Designer, Sr. Interaction Designer at Ning — 2006–2009

I was designer and client-side developer for Ning's primary product, "Your Own Social Network," which allowed people to easily create and customize their own social networks.

- Designed and built the front-end of the initial product, collaborating with 1 other designer
- Initiated and led a redesign of the invitation and sign-up flows that fueled rapid growth to 36 million users and 1.6 million social networks by 2009
- Worked with all areas and levels of the company, including engineering, product management, the support team, and daily collaboration with the CEO
- In my role as Lead Designer, I managed the team of designers and front-end developers responsible for all interaction design, graphic design, and HTML & css code.

362 Missouri Street San Francisco, ca 94107 (415) 609-7490 david@davidlwarner.com http://davidlwarner.com Recruited talent for the design team: identified candidates, reviewed resumes and
portfolios, ran phone screens, selected the most promising candidates for on-site interviews,
conducted interviews, participated in hiring conversations.

Front-End Developer at Adaptive Path, Allstate — 2005–2006

I was contracted by Adaptive Path to build a functional prototype for an insurance-quoting web application for Allstate.

- Responsible for building all HTML, css, JavaScript and graphics
- Collaborated with developers and designers from Adaptive Path and Allstate
- Built another prototype for a similar project at Allstate after Adaptive Path's contract

Web Development Director & Technical Director at POP — 2002–2005

At POP, an interactive agency in Seattle, I was responsible for the technical success of several clients, including InfoSpace, the Seattle Arts Coalition, and online ticketing systems for the Indianapolis Symphony Orchestra, Houston Symphony, and Houston Ballet.

- Managed a team of 5 full-time web developers
- Updated the company's coding standards to css-based XHTML layout
- Interviewed, hired and managed web development contractors
- · Worked with clients, designers, developers, and producers to meet deadlines and budgets
- Developed the front-end of websites for clients including the Metropolitan Opera, the Seattle Opera, and the Mars Rovers Science Team

Program Manager, Applications Engineer at RealNetworks — 1998–2001

- Managed development for the RealSlideshow product and the My Channels program, supporting over 50 companies that launched daily multimedia presentations, including ABC News, CNN and NPR
- Spoke at conferences and represented RealNetworks, including Internet World, Flash Forward, and the Real Conference

Web Developer at Razorfish — 1996

• Hand-coded websites for clients including PepsiCo, IBM, Ralph Lauren and Spencer Tunick

## **EDUCATION**

Oberlin College, Oberlin, OH — BA, Computer Science, 1997